<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="motivationalArray">
        <item>"First you take a drink, then the drink takes a drink, then the drink takes you." — F. Scott Fitzgerald, The Great Gatsby</item>
        <item>"Always do sober what you said you\'d do when you were drunk. That will teach you to keep your mouth shut!” — Ernest Hemingway</item>
        <item>“As an alcoholic, you will violate your standards quicker than you can lower them.” — Robin Williams, Weapons of Self-Destruction</item>
        <item>“It’s a great advantage not to drink among hard drinking people.”
― F. Scott Fitzgerald, The Great Gatsby </item>
        <item>“Better to sleep with a sober cannibal than a drunk Christian.”
― Herman Melville, Moby-Dick or, the Whale </item>
        <item>“Of course, it is very important to be sober when you take an exam. Many worthwhile careers in the street-cleansing, fruit-picking and subway-guitar-playing industries have been founded on a lack of understanding of this simple fact.”
― Terry Pratchett, Moving Pictures </item>
        <item>“When you quit drinking you stop waiting.”
― Caroline Knapp, Drinking: A Love Story </item>
        <item>“Your best days are ahead of you. The movie starts when the guy gets sober and puts his life back together; it doesn\'t end there.”
― Bucky Sinister, Get Up: A 12-Step Guide to Recovery for Misfits, Freaks, and Weirdos </item>
        <item>“Blind, broke, jobless, and frustrated, Kevin found it difficult to get through the following few months. But he had one big thing going for him.
He was sober.
It was a new beginning.”
― Traci Medford-Rosow, Unblinded: One Man’s Courageous Journey through Darkness to Sight </item>
        <item>“I personally believe this: We have only today; yesterday\'s gone and tomorrow is uncertain. That\'s why they call it the present. And sobriety really is a gift... for those who are willing to receive it.”
― Ace Frehley, No Regrets: A Rock \'n\' Roll Memoir </item>
        <item>“Which is recorded of Socrates, that he was able both to abstain from, and to enjoy, those things which many are too weak to abstain from, and cannot enjoy without excess. But to be strong enough both to bear the one and to be sober in the other is the mark of a man who has a perfect and invincible soul.”
― Marcus Aurelius, Meditations </item>
        <item>“We have learned that the satisfaction of instincts cannot be the sole aim of our lives.”
― Alcoholics Anonymous World Services, Twelve Steps and Twelve Traditions </item>
        <item>“My mind may be sober, but my confidence is high!”
― Habeeb Akande </item>
        <item>“To sober up seems to many like making life “so serious,” as if seriousness precluded joy, warmth, spontaneity and fun. But there can be a delusional, blind quality to non-sober festivities. To have our eyes open soberly with all our senses and memory intact allows some of the most rewarding, soul-nourishing, and long-lasting pleasures possible.”
― Alexandra Katehakis, Mirror of Intimacy: Daily Reflections on Emotional and Erotic Intelligence </item>
        <item>“We want ecstasy as a way of life, not a liver-poisoning alcoholiday from it.”
― Crimethinc, Anarchy and Alcohol </item>
        <item>“I had no idea what time I’d left, how I’d gotten home, who’d been up here, and how long he, she, or they had stayed. Another night, added to the hundreds that had gone before, shrouded in mystery. Really, when you thought about it, it was creepy. My own life was a secret to me.”
― Heather King, Parched </item>
        <item>“I wanted a drink. There were a hundred reasons why a man will want a drink, but I wanted one now for the most elementary reason of all. I didn\'t want to feel what I was feeling, and a voice within was telling me that I needed a drink, that I couldn\'t bear it without it.

But that voice is a liar. You can always bear the pain. It\'ll hurt, it\'ll burn like acid in an open wound, but you can stand it. And, as long as you can make yourself go on choosing the pain over the relief, you can keep going.”
― Lawrence Block, Out on the Cutting Edge </item>
        <item>“Just as others pray daily, you should think to yourself daily about what you can do to be closer to this Ideal Image. Think: "What can I do today to make my life better?" "What can I do to become more like my Ideal Image?”
― Bucky Sinister, Get Up: A 12-Step Guide to Recovery for Misfits, Freaks, and Weirdos </item>
        <item>“Was I being groomed for some special mission? What possible purpose could an existence like mine serve? When I wasn’t drinking in crappy bars, I was home by myself reading: a life that was achingly lonely, and yet perversely designed to prevent anybody from ever getting close enough to really know me.”
― Heather King, Parched </item>
        <item>“Courage is what makes us do the right thing even when nobody else is doing it.”
― Bill Pittman, Drop The Rock: Removing Character Defects - Steps Six and Seven </item>
        <item>“Plotting the course away from booze is every bit as hard as leaving an abusive lover – take it from me. In some ways I would even argue it can be harder.... But that safety is not real. The love of your life is a snake in your bed. He offers you escape from all the big meanies and scaries, while he quietly tightens the noose around your neck and the bindings on your wrists and ankles.

When others try to save you from him, he whispers in your ear “They don’t know you like I do, love you like I do. I am all you need.”
― Lore- Boozemusings </item>
        <item>“...being sober delivered almost everything drinking promised.”
― Anne Lamott, Hallelujah Anyway: Rediscovering Mercy </item>
        <item>“For all the alcoholics and addicts out there, you are loved, stopped being so stubborn and come in from the cold. Wherever you are, there is a brighter light in your sight. Move towards it every day, and keep moving towards it. Even the worst and strongest addiction is a choice—a choice not to fight, to give up, to indulge the impulse, or instead to accept the hands offered you to help, even from strangers, even from the state. Don’t hate those who gave up on you, it wasn’t their fault, you just wore them down. Show them they were wrong about you. Your troubles are meant to mold you into something better, not destroy you, so FIGHT! Another day comes for the better if you’re standing in the right spot for it to hit you. Find the right spot and stay there until it does.”
― Dave Pryor </item>
        <item>“Because I just don\'t really care about what the liquid in my glass says about me anymore. I\'d like to tell you it\'s because sobriety cured my need for specialness. I\'d like to tell you I invented the stapler and can start fires with my mind. But no.”
― Kristi Coulter, Nothing Good Can Come from This </item>
        <item>“Addiction puts you in a prison where the locks are on the inside. Only you hold the keys to set yourself free.”
― Toni Sorenson </item>
        <item>“They say getting sober in AA is simple, but not easy. Just like winning the lottery, I guess.”
― Dmitry Dyatlov </item>
        <item>“Speaking a painful truth should be done only in love - like wielding a sword with no hilt - it should pain oneself in direct proportion to the amount of force exerted.”
― Criss Jami, Healology </item>
        <item>“Now I’m
sober and I
realize, I
didn’t drink to
escape the world,
I drank to escape
myself”
― Phil Volatile, Crushed Black Velvet </item>
        <item>“Someone who is trying to be sober is often trying to work out deeper emotional issues and is attempting to undo years of habitual behavior. When you reduce recovery to just abstinence, it simplifies what is really a much more complex issue.”
― Sasha Bronner </item>
        <item>“When one looks at the world directly, the eyes fixate the assemblage point, and no more movement is possible. Under such conditions there can be no fluidity or sobriety. Therefore one should not look at the world directly; that is, one should not stare, but glance around casually and at ease. This is true even if one is using the inner vision to look at one\'s own inner world.”
― Théun Mares, Cry of the Eagle: The Toltec Teachings Volume 2 </item>
        <item>“Sitting on the train to Atlanta, Frank suddenly realized that those memories, powerful as they were, did not crush him anymore or throw him into paralyzing despair. He could recall every detail, every sorrow, without needing alcohol to steady him. Was this the fruit of sobriety?”
― Toni Morrison, Home </item>
        <item>“Sometimes…
Sometimes doubt is the opposite of faith, but sometimes doubt can be a pathway to faith.
Sometimes weakness is the opposite of strength, but sometimes weakness can be the pathway to strength.
Sometimes addiction is the opposite of sobriety, but sometimes addiction can be the pathway to sobriety.
Sometimes infidelity is the opposite of fidelity, but sometimes infidelity can be a pathway to fidelity.
Sometimes failure is the opposite of success, but sometimes failure can be the pathway to success.”
― David W. Jones, Enough: and Other Magic Words to Transform Your Life </item>
        <item>“Hit the bottom and get back up; or hit the bottle and stay down.”
― Anthony Liccione </item>
        <item>“Be grateful. These feelings, no matter how painful, are part of
living. Today, we are alive—not anesthetized, not sedated, not passed
out. Take control of your feelings and through action you can change.
Today, as every day of sober living, we have a choice.”
― Ann D. Clark, Women and Recovery: Sex, Sobriety and Stepping Up: Practical Suggestions for Quality Living in Recovery </item>
        <item>“achieving true sobriety goes beyond abstinence. it\'s also about healing your soul, apologizing for damage you did to other, and seeking forgiveness.”
― Lou Gramm, Juke Box Hero: My Five Decades in Rock \'n\' Roll </item>
        <item>“When was the last time you woke up and wished you\'d had just one more drink the night before?

I have never regretted not drinking. Say this to yourself, and you\'ll get through anything.”
― Meredith Bell, Seven Days Sober: A Guide to Discovering What You Really Think About Your Drinking </item>
        <item>“I wrote this book to show you that a cure is entirely possible because I\'ve seen it happen over and over again.”
― Chris Prentiss, The Alcoholism and Addiction Cure </item>
        <item>“It always seems impossible until it’s done.” -Nelson Mandela</item>
        <item>“You don’t have to be great to start, but you have to start to be great.” -Zig Ziglar</item>
        <item>The key to success is to focus on goals, not obstacles.</item>
        <item>If you can dream it, you can do it.</item>
        <item>Obstacles are the cost of greatness.</item>
        <item>“With the new day comes new strength and new thoughts.” -Eleanor Roosevelt</item>
        <item>Sometimes we’re tested not to show our weakness, but to discover our strengths.</item>
        <item>Don’t stop until you’re proud.</item>
        <item>Wake up with determination, go to bed with satisfaction.</item>
        <item>A smooth sea never made a skilled sailor.</item>
        <item>Don’t let what you cannot do interfere with what you can do.</item>
        <item>Doubt kills more dreams than failure ever will.</item>
        <item>Success doesn’t come from what you do occasionally, it comes from what you do consistently.</item>
        <item>A problem is a chance for you to do your best.</item>
        <item>Be stronger than your strongest excuse.</item>
        <item>Everything is theoretically impossible, until it is done.</item>
        <item>Nothing is impossible. The word itself says “I’m Possible.”</item>
        <item>If it doesn’t challenge you, it won’t change you.</item>
        <item>Your health is an investment, not an expense.</item>
        <item>Attitude is a little thing that makes a big difference.</item>
        <item>You are your only limit.</item>
        <item>When you feel like quitting, think about why you started.</item>
        <item>Every next level of your life will demand a different version of you.</item>
        <item>When feeling overwhelmed by a faraway goal, repeat the following: I have it within me right now, to get me to where I want to be later.</item>
        <item>Mindset is what separates the best from the rest.</item>
        <item>Surround yourself with people who see your value and remind you of it.</item>
        <item>Believe you can and you’re halfway there.</item>
        <item>Make the most of yourself by fanning the tiny, inner sparks of possibility into flames of achievement.</item>
        <item>Never give up. Everyone has bad days - pick yourself up and keep going!</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>